

CLOUD-NATIVE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

11200 Greenwood Ave N., 34, Seattle, WA 98133

□ (206) 954-1418 | ■ erstaples@gmail.com | □ erstaples | ■ erstaples | □ erstaples

Summary_

Current Software Engineer on the NetApp Kubernetes Service (NKS) team at NetApp. 7+ years experience specializing in Kubernetes, cloud-native engineering, and infrastructure automation. Hard worker who has a penchant for Bash scripts and strong coffee. Interested in helping to shape the future of cloud-native applications and architecture.

Skills

Technologies Kubernetes/Kubebuilder/Controller Runtime, gRPC, Docker, Terraform, Ansible, Prometheus, Grafana, EFK stack

Languages Go, Protobuf, PHP, Python, Bash, JavaScript **OSS Contributions** Cluster API, Cluster API Provider AWS, Helm Charts

Professional Experience ___

NetApp Seattle, WA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2019 - Present

- Designed and developed in Golang the cluster provision system that is the backbone of "NKS" (NetApp Kubernetes Service), a multi-cloud, production-grade, managed Kubernetes offering that leverages several upstream Kubernetes SIG (special interest group) projects.
- · Built Ansible playbooks and provided documentation for the support team to provide services to NKS customers more efficiently.
- · Collaborated with front-end team to design and develop an API for the build system using gRPC.
- · Contributed to Cluster API Kubernetes SIG via Github pull requests and issues, Zoom office hours and Slack discussions.

Drud Seattle, WA

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER

Jul. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- Operated and iterated on "DDEV Live", a Kubernetes-based web-hosting platform and deployment pipeline for hundreds of CMS websites.
- Established and executed plan to deliver 99.99% uptime guarantee by implementing self-healing HA platform with resource-based autoscaling.
- Instrumented, configured, and tuned observability and monitoring stack using Prometheus metrics and alert dashboard, Fluentd, and LogDNA, with VictorOps and Slack integrations, which provided the foundation for new on-call rotations.

MedBridge Seattle, WA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / DEVOPS ENGINEER

Jan. 2015 - Jul. 2018

Mar. 2014 - Dec. 2014

- Led effort to move deployment platform from Puppet to Kubernetes, which included translating Puppet manifests into Dockerfiles and Kubernetes specs and adopting technologies such as KOPS, Helm, Minikube, ELK stack, Kubectl, and Calico network policies.
- Developed a set of Golang and Bash tools to automate deployments and bootstrap dev machines with a local Minikube cluster.
- Reviewed and updated MedBridge services to ensure they met cloud-native best practices.
- Designed active-active failover system to ensure MedBridge services met and exceeded SLA requirements.
- Implemented cluster monitoring, logging, and alerting system using several open source projects.
- · Containerized / Dockerized PHP, Golang, and Node applications and wrote manifest files to bring them to life in a Kubernetes cluster.

HCSS Sugar Land, TX

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Built tools in C#/.NET to manage and sync data between Azure and on-prem servers.
- · Wrote custom reports in SQL based on customer needs.

R.R. Donnelley Houston, TX

Web Programmer

Dec. 2012 - Mar. 2014

• Developed UIs in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for web-to-print, variable-data print products.

Education

University of Washington Seattle, WA

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN ENGLISH LANGUAGE AND LITERATURE

2011

• 3.82 GPA